odin.com 2015-05-26

# Parallels Privacy Policy - Odin

Updated December 2014 

Parallels (“we”, “us”, “our”) knows that information privacy and security are important to you and we are committed to protecting the information you entrust to our care. Knowing our customers helps us to better serve them, so we place a high value of protecting personal information. 

In this Privacy Notice, we describe the information that we collect from individuals who visit our website, use our products, contact us for support, and conduct business or exchange communications with us. We describe the type of information we collect, use, share, and protect it. By using our website, products and/or services you agree to the practices described in this Privacy Notice. 

## Information Collection

Parallels gathers information in most of our interactions with prospects and customers, whether directly or indirectly. Some of the information we collect is personally identifiable – that is, we can use it to identify, locate or contact you as an individual. Much of the information we collect is not personally identifiable. 

### Information You Provide

We collect and store your information when you register products, create an online profile, make an inquiry or contact us for support, as well as other contacts. You can withhold information, though this might make it difficult for us to provide certain services that depend on that information. Examples of your information we collect include:

  * Contacts such as names, postal and email addresses, phone numbers;
  * Payment data such as payment cards and bank accounts;
  * Billing, shipping and other purchasing and shipping information;
  * Records of transactions, including purchases, inquiries and service requests;
  * Authentication data such as user name and password to verify access. 

### Information Collected Automatically

We may collect and store information about how you use our website(s) and applications, including your use of a desktop feature that takes you online. For visitors to our website(s) we collect IP address, browser type and other information such as search terms. For callers to our support service center, for example, we may collect the phone number used to facilitate communicating with you. 

We use cookies on our website to remember user preferences and to enhance our website services. Cookies are small identifiers we transfer to your computer to enable our systems to recognize your device and to provide features and advertising. You can learn more about cookies and controlling how your computer accepts and stores cookies and similar identifiers by clicking [here](http://www./). You can block cookies though this might disable certain features that you find convenient. In general, information we collect through cookies does not identify you. 

### Information from Applications (Parallels Desktop and Parallels Access)

Parallels collects limited information from users of our desktop and mobile applications, including product registration information, non-identifying indicators of operating system version, IP address, referring URL’s and other information about your use of the product. 

### Minimizing Personal Information Collection

We strive to collect only that information needed to serve the purpose requested by the individual and to maintain only that personal information that is relevant to those purposes. 

## Information Uses

Parallels uses your information to serve you and meet your needs to our best ability. For example, when you use our website, the cookie helps recognize you and your preferences. We use your product purchase and registration information to keep you informed about updates, patches and other advisories. We use it to process your purchases, manage subscriptions, send messages and provide product support. 

We also use your information for research into improving our products and services, for planning new features and updates and to customize and improve our websites. For the safety of our customers and employees, we may use information we collect to detect and prevent potential or actual claims and prohibited behaviors, such as fraud or attempts to breach our information security. 

## Information Sharing

In order to serve your requests and needs, we work with trusted third parties that help us run our business. These companies may process payments, fulfill orders, send email or conduct other activities on our behalf. We only share the information needed by them to serve the specific purpose for which they are engaged and we do not allow them to use your information for unauthorized purposes. 

We share your information with our business divisions and affiliated companies for purposes described in this notice and only for legitimate business purposes. 

We will share your information when you specifically permit that sharing. And we will share your information when, in good faith, we believe it is necessary to prevent or respond to fraud, defend our interests or protect our customers, employees or the public. We may disclose personal information if we are required to by law or legal process or in response to requests by government agencies or as required for national security. 

Should Parallels merge with or be acquired by another company or we sell product lines, service activities or other assets, it is likely your information will be transferred as is appropriate and relevant. 

We may share aggregated and anonymized information (non-identifying) such as statistics about website visitors, product users or other uses of our products and services. 

## Information Choices for Use & Sharing

Parallels provides you the opportunity to choose how we use your information and with whom we share it. You may choose to not provide your information, though that will likely prevent us from providing certain services. You can choose to receive or to stop receiving Parallels marketing materials, newsletters and subscriptions. We retain the right to send customers messages concerning purchases, critical updates and other administratively necessary information. You cannot opt-out of these messages. 

You may give or withhold permission for Parallels to share your information for marketing purposes with trusted vendors and partners. You can make and manage your choices by signing in to the “My Account” feature on our website. You can also respond to our electronic communications and subscriptions with an “Unsubscribe” message in the subject field. 

## Information Access for Changes

Our website and applications allow you to edit your personal information by accessing the “My Account” or similar feature of the website or application you are using. We protect our customers’ privacy and security by limiting the amount of information you can access and edit. You may be able to delete some, but not all, information, as our legal obligations require that we retain specific information for legal and internal business reasons. If you do change your current information, you should be aware that the previous record may be retained on backup records, in compliance with applicable law. 

## Information Security

We use administrative, physical and technical safeguards to protect personal information. We utilize encryption technologies for sensitive data sent from our web sites. We deploy reasonable safeguards across our company databases to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure or loss of personal information. We require our vendors and agents to use safeguards that protect information at least at the same level as our own safeguards. 

## Information Retention & Destruction

We maintain customer information for as long as we need it to provide the requested services. When personal information is no longer needed to serve the purpose of its collection, we strive to de-identify the data, creating aggregated, anonymous records to aid our research and to improve our products, services, and communications. When we do discard personal information, we employ data destruction techniques designed to completely destroy data and prevent any future recovery. 

## Information Inquiries

Individuals who have questions about our personal information handling policies and procedures can contact us at privacy(at)parallels.com
